Finding Aid for the Lejaren Hiller Collection of Audio Tape Recordings, 1958-1985
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Five Appalachian ballads, for voice and guitar/harpsichord (1958) (H. 24), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, mono., Head out,; Possibly unique performances Performers: H. 24 performed by Phyllis Hurt and Roger Shields; H. 27 performed by Elizabeth Hiller; H. 40 performed 
  H. 27, Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (3 excerpts)
  H. 40, An avalanche, for pitchman, prima donna and percussion (1968)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Divertimento for eleven instruments (1959) (H. 25), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; "Edited version" Performers: Radio Kamerorkest (VPRO), Vilversum; Ernest Bour, conductor Duration: 37:28 Edited version Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 046)
  I. Fanfare and Furioso 8:02 II. Nocturne 7:50 III. Five Structures 7:03 IV. Scherzo with Trio 4:25 V. Capriccio and Coda 9:52 0:16
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Divertimento for eleven instruments (1959) (H. 25), H. 27 performance April 1964, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Sub-Master tape Submaster Performers: H. 25 performed by Radio Kamerorkest (VPRO), Hilversum; Ernest Bour, conductor; H. 27 performed by Elizabeth Hiller, Judith Hoppe, Charles Rogers, Royal MacDonald, directed by Lionel Lawrence Duration: 39:59 (H. 25) H. 25 spine label: master tape; H. 27 spine label: roundhouse tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 047)
  I. Fanfare and Furioso 8:02 II. Nocturne 7:50 III. Five Structures 7:03 IV. Scherzo with Trio 5:27 V. Capriccio and Coda 11:21 0:16
  H. 27, Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic music for "Blue is the antecedent of it", a one-act play by Jack Leckel (1959) (H. 26), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono., Tail out; Cue tape Duplicate of Master cue tape 50 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 048)
  I. Overture II. Dance of Origins III. Entry of the Cross IV. Four Cheers V. Chorus I VI. Sound Effect VII. Sound Effect VIII. Chorus II IX. Chorus III, Three Pantomimes and Chorus IV X. Finale
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic music for "Blue is the antecedent of it", a one-act play by Jack Leckel (1959) (H. 26), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips., full-track mono.; Extra copy for performance use; can also use as cue tape Duplicate of Master cue tape 50 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 049)
  I. Overture 1:48 II. Dance of the Origins III. Entry of the Cross IV. Four Cheers V. Chorus I VI. Sound Effect I VII. Sound Effect II VIII. Chorus II IX. Chorus III; Three Pantomimes; Chorus IV X. Finale
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic music for "Blue is the antecedent of it", a one-act play by Jack Leckel (1959) (H. 26), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape master Cue tape master Duration: 19:00 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 050)
  I. Overture 1:48 II. Dance of the Origins 3:06 III. Entry of the Cross 1:02 IV. Four Cheers 0:18 V. Chorus I 0:48 VI. Sound Effect 0:08 VII. Sound Effect II 0:08 VIII. Chorus II 0:43 IX. Chorus III; Three Pantomimes; Chorus IV 7:30 X. Finale 2:48 18:24 Leaders 0:36
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Electronic music for "Blue is the antecedent of it", a one-act play by Jack Leckel (1959) (H. 26), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape Duplicate of Master cue tape 50 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 051)
  I. Overture II. Dance of the Origins III. Entry of the Cross IV. Four Cheers V. Chorus I VI. Sound Effects I VII. Sound Effects II VIII. Chorus II IX. Chorus III; Three Pantomimes; Chorus IV X. Finale
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape Duplicate of Master Cue Tape 56 Copy 1 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 052)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape Duplicate of Master Cue Tape 56 Copy 2 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 053)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), Recorded 1975 at Baird Hall, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Duplicate of Master tape 55 Performers: Cressida Bound: Tess Spangler; Imogen Bound: Anne Gayley; Tobias Bound: Gary Burke; Augustus Bound: David Lamb; Directed by Elizabeth Hiller Duration: 30:00 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 054)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), Recorded July 10, 1975, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, Dolby A, tail out; Master tape Performers: Cressida Bound: Tess Spangler Imogen Bound: Anne Gayley Tobias Bound: Gary Burke Augustus Bound: David Lamb Directed by Elizabeth Hiller Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 055)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape master Master cue tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 056)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Cuthbert Bound, chamber music for four actors and tape recorder, text by Christopher Newton (1960) (H. 27), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape Duplicate of Master cue tape 56 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 057)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Symphony, No. 2 (1960) (H. 28), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo; Unique performance Performers: Buffalo Philharmonic; Lukas Foss, conductor Duration: 38:34 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 058)
  I. Sonata Allegro 8:16 II. Ballad 7:00 III. Scherzo 12:24 IV. Passacaglia 10:42
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Sonata, No. 5 for piano (1961) (H. 29), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo; Duplicate of Master tape 60 Performers: Kenwyn Boldt, piano Duration: 26:00 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 059)
  I. Sonata Allegro: Andante Tranquillo, Allegro 8:09 Agitate II. Interlude: Lentissimo 12:31 III. Rondo: Presto 3:33 IV. Finale: Allegro Moderato and Prestissimo 1:55 25:48 Spacers 0:12
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Sonata, No. 5 for piano (1961) (H. 29), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, Dolby A301 stretched; Dolby noise reduction, Tail out; Master tape Duration: 26:00 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 060)
  I. Sonata Allegro: Andante Tranquillo, Allegro Agitate 8:09 II. Interlude: Lentissimo 12:31 II. Rondo: Presto 3:33 III. Finale: Allegro Moderato and Prestissimo 1:55 25:48 Spacers 0:12
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for a film "Time of the heathen" (1961) (H. 30a), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Presumed duplicate of Master tape 62 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 061)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for a film "Time of the heathen" (1961) (H. 30), Recorded May 1961, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, Tail out; Master tape Performers: University of Illinois Wind Ensemble; Robert Gray, conductor Duration: 27:18 Original performance minus electronic music; Original scoring Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 062)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for a film "Time of the heathen" (1961) (H. 30), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono. (H. 30, H. 32); 2-channel stereo (H. 36), Tail out; Cue tapes Cue tapes Duration: ca. 12:16 (H. 30); ca. 4:15 (H. 32); ca. 11:59 (H. 36) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 063)
  Cue 1: For I (Overture) 0:41 Cue 2: For VII (Introduction and Round) 0:54 Cue 3: For X (Nightmare Music) 10:41
  H. 32, Amplification, for tape recorder and jazz band (1962) Cue 1: 0:18 Cue 2: 2:10 Cue 3: 1:18 Cue 4: 0:29 See Score for Entries
  H. 36, Computer cantata, for soprano, tape and chamber ensemble (1963), composed with R. A. Baker Cue 1: For Strophe I 4:24 Cue 2: For Strophe II 0:55 Cue 3: For Prolog to Strophe III 1:51 Cue 4: For Epilog to Strophe IV 1:56 Cue 5: For Strophe V 1:53
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Suite from "Time of the Heathen" (1961) (H. 30a), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, stereo, tail out,; Storage tapes Unique performances of H. 30a and H. 44 Performers: H. 30a: UB Student Orchestra, conducted by James Kasprowicz; H. 44: original performance by Jan Williams and Howard Zwicker H. 30a: revised orchestration Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 064)
  H. 44, Three rituals, for two percussion, projections and lights (1969)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Nightmare music, for tape alone (From "The time of the heathen") 1961 (H. 30b), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono (H. 30b, H. 32); 2-channel stereo (H. 36), Tail out; Cue tapes Cue tapes Duration: 11:35 (H. 30b); ca. 4:15 (H. 32); ca. 10:59 (H. 36) Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 065)
  H. 32, Amplification, for tape recorder and jazz band (1962) Cue 1: 0:18 Cue 2: 2:10 Cue 3: 1:18 Cue 4: 0:29
  H. 36, Computer cantata, for soprano, tape and chamber ensemble (1963), composed with R. A. Baker Cue 1: For Strophe I 4:24 Cue 2: For Strophe II 0:55 Cue 3: Prolog to Strophe III 1:51 Cue 4: Epilog to Strophe III 1:56 Cue 5: For Strophe IV 1:53
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Nightmare music, for tape alone (From "The time of the heathen") (1961) (H. 30b), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Possible unique performance Performers: H. 32: UB Jazz Band, conducted by Lee Bash Duration: 11:35 (H. 30b); 9:50 (H. 32) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 066)
  H. 32, Amplification, for tape recorder and jazz band (1962), new scoring (1983)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Nightmare music, for tape alone (From "The time of the heathen") (1961) (H. 30b), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips and 7 ½ ips, full-track mono.; Master tapes, also cue tape master (H. 32) Master cue tapes Duration: 11:35 (H. 30b); 9:55 complete performance, 4:15 cue tape master (H. 32) H. 30b is on front of the tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 067)
  H. 32, Amplification, for tape recorder and jazz band (1962) (a) Complete Performance (b) Cue Tape Master Cue 1: 0:18 Cue 2: 2:10 Cue 3: 1:18 Cue 4: 0:29
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 String quartet No. 5, "In quarter-tones" (1962) (H. 31), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; If tape is in poor condition, use Tape 13 storage tape Performers: Concord String Quartet Duration: 26:58 (taken from VoxBox SB5406) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 068)
  I. Theme I II. Variations 1 to 4 III. Theme 2 IV. Variations 5 to 8 V. Theme 3 VI. Variations 9 to 12 VII. Theme 4
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "The man with the oboe" (1962) (H. 33), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, full-track mono.; Cue tape Cue tape (see cue sheet in score) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 069)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "The man with the oboe" (1962) (H. 33), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Different performance from Tape 71 Performers: Ensembles conducted by John Garvey and James Kasprowicz Duration: 25:51 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 070)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Music for "The man with the oboe" (1962) (H. 33), Recorded February, 6, 1963, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono., Tail out; Master tape Master tape Performers: Chamber Ensemble conducted by John Garvey and Lejaren Hiller Duration: 25:24 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 071)
  I. Overture 0:58 II. Piper’s Song- Part One 3:03 III. Serenade and Politician’s March 4:00 IV. Act Change Music 1:50 V. Ballet of the Three Pickpockets and The Tart 7:57 VI. Hillbilly Song 1:55 VII. TV Jingle and Fanfare 0:50 VIII. South Sea Music 1:05 IX. Funeral March 2:17 X. Piper’s Song- Part Two 2:05 XI. Finale
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Spoon River, Illinois, for narrators and instrumental sextet (1962) (H. 34), Recorded December 1, 1977, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Possibly unique performance (note difference in conductor) Performers: Tess Spangler, Paul Schmidt with Ensemble conducted by James Kasprowicz Duration: 26:30 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 072)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Spoon River, Illinois, for narrators and instrumental sextet (1962) (H. 34), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, tail out; Master tape Master tape Performers: Lejaren Hiller, conductor Original recording for WCIA Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 073)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Seven electronic studies, for two-channel tape recorder (1963) (H. 35), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Duplicate of Master tape 75 Duration: 24:00 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 074)
  I. Vocalise II. Just Proportions III. Homage to Helmholtz IV. Two-Part Invention V. Ordered Disorder VI. Even-Tempered Scherzo VII. Peroration
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Seven electronic studies, for two-channel tape recorder (1963) (H. 35), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo, Tail out; Master tape Master tape Duration: 24:21(including 0:04 between each movement) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 075)
  1. Vocalise 0 dB 5:32 2. Proportions -2 dB 1:32 3. Homage to Helmholtz +3 dB 4:15 4. Two-Part Invention 0 dB 1:05 5. Ordered Disorder +3 dB 4:10 6. Even-Tempered Scherzo 0 dB 1:25 7. Peroration 0 dB 5:38
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Computer cantata, for soprano, tape and chamber ensemble (1963), composed with R. A. Baker (H. 36), Recorded December 8 and 11, 1963, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo, Tail out; For performance; cues already transferred to CD for Andrew Stiller Performers: University of Illinois Percussion Ensemble conducted by Jack McKenzie; Helen Hamm, soprano Duration: 24:00 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 076)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Machine music, for piano, percussion and tape (1964) (H. 37), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo; Unique performance of H. 37 H. 39 performance duplicate on Tape 87 Performers: H. 37: Roger Shields, piano; Jeffrey Kowalsky, percussion; H. 39: Roger Shields, piano; Neely Bruce, piano Duration: 13:28 (H. 37); 18:38 (H. 39) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 077)
  H. 39, Suite for two pianos and tape (1966)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Machine music, for piano, percussion and tape (1964) (H. 37), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Cue tapes Possible alternative source for H. 43 cue tapes (see Tape 133 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 078)
  H. 43, Computer music, for percussion and tape (1968), composed with G. Allan O'Conner
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Machine music, for piano, percussion and tape (1964) (H. 37), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo.; Complete performance submaster; cue tape master Cue tapes Performers: Phyllis Rappeport, piano; Thomas Silve, percussion; Burt Levy, tape recorder Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 079)
  (1) Complete Performance Submaster (2) Cue Tape Master Cue 1: Trio I Cue 2: Duo I Cue 3: Solo III Cue 4: Solo IV Cue 5: Duo III Cue 6: Trio II
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Machine music, for piano, percussion and tape (1964) (H. 37), H. 37 recorded December 1971; H. 45 recorded May 10, 1971, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A301 stretched, Tail out; Master recordings Master tape Performers: H. 37: Jeffrey Kowalsky, percussion; Roger Shields, piano; H. 45: Mark Sokol, violin; Roger Shields, piano Duration: 13:02 (H. 37); 15:30 (H. 45) N.Y. Studio original of Solo II of Machine Music on front of tape Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 080)
  H. 45, Sonata, No. 3 for violin and piano (1970) I. Furioso 3:32 II. Largo 7:54 III. Prestissimo 3:56 Spacers 0:08
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Machine music, for piano, percussion and tape (1964) (H. 37), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo; Cue tapes Cue tapes Possibly duplicate material (see Tapes 79, 88, and 133), but notation for H. 43 on Tape 133 mentions different versions, so this should be recorded as backup Information from spine Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 081)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Triptych for Hieronymus (1966) (H. 38), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Cue tape Duplicate of Master Tape 85 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 082)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Triptych for Hieronymus (1966) (H. 38), Recorded February 17, 1973, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Duplicate of Master tape 84 Performers: Chamber Orchestra directed by Jan Williams Duration: 41:16 Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 083)
  I. Frame 0:52 II. The Garden of Eden 14:14 III. First Entr’acte 2:02 IV. The Carnival of Live 13:46 V. Second Entr’acte 2:01 VI. Hell 6:17 VII. Frame 0:50
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Triptych for Hieronymus (1966) (H. 38), Recorded February 17, 1973, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Dolby A301 stretched; Master tape Master performance tape Performers: Theater Orchestra conducted by Jan Williams Duration: 41:16 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 084)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Triptych for Hieronymus (1966) (H. 38), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tape master Master cue tapes Duration: 24:59 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 085)
  Cue 1: Third Day of Creation 2:00 Cue 2: Fauna 0:45 Cue 3: Chorale 1:40 Cue 4: Dance of Death 1:40 Cue 5: First Entr’acte 2:00 Cue 6: Barker’s Fugue 1:40 Cue 7: First Takeoff 0:40 Cue 8: Jubilee 1:05 Cue 9: Second Takeoff 0:40 Cue 10: Hurdy Gurdy 2:00 Cue 11: Third Takeoff 0:40 Cue 12: Because It’s You 1:45 Cue 13: Fourth Takeoff 0:40 Cue 14: Billboard Music 1:40 Cue 15: Second Entr’acte 2:00 Cue 16: The Junction 2:30 Cue 17: Conclusion 0:30 16 Four-Second Spaces 1:04
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Triptych for Hieronymus (1966) (H. 38), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Cue tape Submaster Submaster duplicate of Master tape 85 Duration: 25:00 Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 086)
  Cue 1: Third Day of Creation 2:00 Cue 2: Fauna 0:45 Cue 3: Chorale 1:40 Cue 4: Dance of Death 1:40 Cue 5: First Entr’acte 2:00 Cue 6: Barker’s Fugue 1:40 Cue 7: First Takeoff 0:40 Cue 8: Jubilee 1:05 Cue 9: Second Takeoff 0:40 Cue 10: Hurdy Gurdy 2:00 Cue 11: Third Takeoff 0:40 Cue 12: Because It’s You 1:45 Cue 13: Fourth Takeoff 0:40 Cue 14: Billboard Music 1:40 Cue 15: Second Entr’acte 2:00 Cue 16: The Junction 2:30 Cue 17: Conclusion 0:30 16 Spacers 1:04
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Suite for two pianos and tape (1966) (H. 39), Recorded January 1968, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Sub-masters, concert performance and cue tape master Submaster and cue tape master Performers: Roger Shields and Neely Bruce, pianos Duration: 18:33 (concert performance) (best copy) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 087)
  A. Concert Performance I. Retrospect 5:02 (a) Animal Dance, (b) Estampie II. Circumspect 10:25 (a) Carnival Time, (b) Sonata A Quatro (b) Magician’s Waltz, (d) Vox Humana (e) Grand Parade IV. Prospect 2:58 (a) Intrada B. Cue Tape Master Cue 1: Fauna; Cue 2: Dance of Death; Cue 3: Barker’s Fugue; Cue 4: Jubilee; Cue 5: Hurdy Gurdy; Cue 6: Because It’s You; Cue 7: Billboard Music; Cue 8: The Junction
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Avalanche, for pitchman, prima donna and percussion (1968) (H. 40), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 2 extra 15 ips and 1extra 7 ½ ips; Extra cue tapes Extra cue tapes also includes player piano recording Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 088)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Avalanche, for pitchman, prima donna and percussion (1968) (H. 40), undated, 1 7 inch reel; speed unknown; Unique performance Performers: H. 40: Royal MacDonald, speaker; Norma Marder, soprano; Robert Rosen, percussion; H. 43a, Jan Williams, percussion H. 43b, Martha Herr, soprano; Laurence Trott, piccolo; John Boudler, percussion Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 089)
  H. 43a, Computer music, for percussion and tape (1968), composed with G. Allan O'Conner
  H. 43b, Computer music, for soprano, piccolo, percussion and tape (1981)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 Avalanche, for pitchman, prima donna and percussion (1968) (H. 40), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 15 ips, full-track mono. and 2-channel stereo., Tail out; Master tapes Master tapes Duration: see note (a) Studio recording, recorded June 1968; 9:04 (b) Depot performance, recorded April 19, 1968; monaural, 11:40 ©) Cue tape master; full-track monaural; Contents: Quotations from Henry Miller, Frank Lloyd Wright, Frank Parman, John Cage, Louis Aragon, Nikolai Lenin, John Philip Sousa (d) Original player piano recording; 6:00 (e) Original recording of "Stars and Stripes"; 7 ½ ips Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 090)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Cue tape Cue tape Cue tape of approximately 1/3 of the original gamuts. To be used primarily with a solo instrument. Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 091)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD - SoloVI (H. 41), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo; Duplicate on Tape 118 Performers: Neely Bruce, harpsichord Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 092)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 7 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, 2-channel stereo.; Duplicate on Tape 119 Performers: David Tudor, Antoinette Vischer, Neely Bruce, harpsichords Duration: 21:00 Collage for Nonesuch Record Tape digitally reformatted: No (Item 093)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 5-6-7 (Reel I of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 094)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 8-9-10 (Reel II of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 095)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 11-12-13 (Reel III of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 096)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 14-15-16 (Reel IV of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 097)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 17-18-19 (Reel V of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 098)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 20-21-22 (Reel VI of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 099)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 23-24-25 (Reel VII of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 100)
- Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 HPSCHD, for 1 to 7 harpsichords and 1 to 51 tapes (1968), composed with John Cage (H. 41), undated, 1 10 inch reel; 7 ½ ips, Tail out,; Master Copy B 26-27-28 (Reel VIII of 18) Tape digitally reformatted: Yes (Item 101)